so now that we understand what a
proposition is let's go ahead and
introduce some notation in particular
because we're writing out these
propositions and the full form like this
can get really tedious so we use some
notation so that notation is referred to
as propositional variables so we use
propositional variables these are also
known as so aka sentential variables and
we use these things to represent
propositions and we typically use the
symbols like p q r s etc to represent
these different propositions and these
variables right here
can I have to take the value of true
because remember a proposition can
either be true or false and so we
usually represent true using a tea right
here or false F so for example instead
of having to write down one plus one
equals two every time I want to refer to
that proposition right there I could
just say well I'm going to define that
to be the propositional variable P and
then this proposition right here I can
define that to be the propositional
variable Q and this longer proposition
right here I can very compactly
represent that simply by using the
propositional variable or sentential
variable R right here and as this
notation right here indicates these
things only take on the value of true or
false so for example if we were to look
at our different variables and also look
at their truth value then in this
particular example right here our prop
up proposition P turns out to be true
because yes indeed one plus one equals
two whereas Q over here that proposition
it takes on the value false right there
and our also happens to be true so these
are propositional variables that have
particular truth values this just gives
us a really compact way to refer to what
could be a very long declarative
sentence right here by the way this
thing right here is referred to as a
truth table and it's going to show up
quite a bit as we talk about
propositional logic